Hey, hey, hey.
Heat. Heat. N.
[Music]
Hello, good evening, good day everybody
and welcome to the 258th episode of the
Ask a Biji Show. I hope everybody is
doing fantastic. This is a super chat
live stream. I've turned super chats
back on today. Yesterday I did not take
any super chats. So super chats are back
on but before we begin with the
questions let me see who all is there on
the live stream on the live chat I can
say GK Juman poor man Chhat Kashab
Shivasai Vicki Manohar Siddesh Patil
Tushar Kalborgi global citizen Samarati
Unabonga Anand Anand Chandak Avin Hunter
Canvi anonymous scientist Hola Sonia Sha
Samripati again geopolitical from Indor
Shivasai unknown
Basant 007 Rahul Dunak IC ICMBBS
Ashish Karan Amar Singh Devil
Pratam Sony Dilling Pengu from Assam
Hello Junai who else do we have Sar
Sharma Anam Chandag MB Br SK Nois X NC
Punit Jashan Sudair Shubagarwal
Shiva Daran Sit Jal Sanchari
Sai Sasank Anu Diptasen Duv Durya Nitin
Kumar Mystic SK Mloin
from Superbad Vishal Patro Adwit Meta
Priyanka Javalia Niha Sharma Edtopia
Maj Hail 06 M50 Chutan Narraadya Shrians
Shreas Mishra really now um who else
jwal Bandekar Bhoji
Dr. Ritwick Patnak from Odish from
Bhineseshwar. Oh wonderful good good
Rahul Takar Prashant Kumar Rudra Avdar
and so many other people. I'm going to
stop the greetings over here and let's
take some questions. So Vidi G is there
nationalist is there Arya Dwan and so on
so forth. Okay, thank you so much all of
you for being on the live stream. Let me
take some questions now. Uh super chats
today. So Pratam Sony says see you as
mentor. Thank you so much. As every
country has its character. Can you tell
five p prominent characters of the
Indian civilization? Every country has
its own character. Five prominent
characters of the Indian civilization.
Or we have Lord Ram, we have Shri
Krishna.
Um we have Vishnu Gupta Chanaka
that's three.
Uh we have Chhatrapat Shivaji Maharaj
and we have the great Chola Father Sanju
Rajendra and Rajar Raj Raj Chola. I
think that's five. I could give 50 more.
I'm sure tremendous people were we
produced tremendous people. But there we
have it. At least five prominent
characters of the Indian civilization.
We have the people who wrote the verses,
the schlokas of the rigida, men and
women and so many other people. I mean I
could go on but yeah five. If you say
five here you have five. I think I give
you six. Devil says during the invasions
many people won, many died and many went
into exile. My question is what
struggles did the Dalit people face at
the time? I am not a historian of Dalith
history. I have no idea. I think we all
faced struggles together as a
civilization and it is a very foreign
imposition on us that we want to slice
our civilization and our population into
ethnic into into uh opposing groups and
we want to deconstruct Indian society
and then look at struggles from a very
particular group's position. We all face
struggles together. But the British and
the Westerners have taught us to see us
ourselves not as a unified civilization
but as separate opposing groups. And
that's why we want to look at what did
this group face and what did that group
face and I my group has been oppressed
for 10,000 years by the white Arian
invaders. All that nonsense these are
all lies. These are lies that are
devised to to make us fight ourselves,
fight each other. And they have told
your teachers, your professors, your
textbooks, they have put all these lies
into your head that so and so group was
oppressed by so and so other group in
India for thousands of years. And
India's India's culture is is a is a
foreign imposition. Sanskrit is foreign
to India. Hinduism is foreign to India.
And there was a cast system that was
used to oppress lower casts. All of this
has been created by outsiders to make us
fight each other. So that's what I have
to say about this matter. I have nothing
further to say about this. Ashish Karan
says, "Why does breakthrough research
require billions of dollars, hundreds of
personnel, etc. and not in basement of
geeks or small scale whatever? Are we at
a point in history where lowhanging
fruits in research are mostly plucked?
Have mostly been plucked. Maybe maybe
not. When it comes to technologies like
AI, you need tremendous amounts of power
to power the GPUs, electricity. So power
is going to be a bottleneck when it
comes to AI to further development in
the scale and complexity and power of AI
systems.
So when it comes to AI and AI is the
very most visible example and robotics
is another most visible example of u you
know technological breakthrough
research. Um
so it looks like these days everything
is like massive massively supercaled
everything requires billions maybe
trillions of dollars etc. But there
could be technological breakthroughs
that could happen in someone's basement
and what those could be I don't know but
it could happen you know there's always
a cycle of this you know when when some
technology takes off and it becomes
bigger and bigger at scale and then
something else comes and upsets
everything you know so yeah at this
point in time it's like that the
technologies that are so visible they
require tremendous investments
uh that's why they happen at the scale
of governments and companies and
countries and super corporations but I'm
Sure some other things will crop up
sooner sooner or later.
ICMBB says if Chunk Kaishek won how
would India's ties with China be
different? You see if you want to see
what kind of ties we would have with the
Chinese government if Chong Kaishek won
all you have to do is see the attitude
of the Taiwanese government towards
India. The Taiwan government considers
itself to be the legitimate government
of all of China. by the way and they
claim Indian territory just like the
Chinese Communist Party they claim
Arunachal Pradesh they claim oxai chin
they claim so so and so so forth other
territories so the if the if the if the
quam in Tang won Changai's party I think
we would have had a similar set of
issues with them so the problem is not
China the problem is us actually that we
allowed them to capture Tibet
we should not have allowed the Chinese
to set food in Tibet. We should have
defended Tibet at our own expense. We
should have done that because that was
vital for our national security.
So it would have made no difference if
Changek won. He would also have had if
the Ku Tang also would have had a very
similar approach with the Chinese
Communist Party. When it comes to um
India,
anonymous scientist says, "How bad are
Israeli strikes in Iran? Will there be a
regime change in in Iran? I have just
briefly seen what happened. It looks
like they've done a decapitation strike
strike on the top leadership in the
military and the various nuclear nuclear
scientists etc. I have just barely
glanced at the news. So I don't know
that this is not a breaking news show
that we do here. This is a deep analysis
show that we do here whether it's the
geo strategy show or or or or the Indian
interest show or this Q&A show. So I've
just barely glanced at what happened. I
don't have a deeply properly informed
view right now of what's happened. Maybe
I will have a better understanding
tomorrow of what's happened. Uh will
there be a regime change in change in
Iran? I hope there is no regime change
in Iran. There are lots of these idiotic
30 IQ Indian right-wingers who are
celebrating right now. Yes.
Israel, our great our great friend full
support Israel has struck at Iran. this
Islamic nation, those idiots have no
idea what Iran represents for us because
when right now you have a regime that is
run by the ayatas and moolas in Iran and
they force their women into burkas and
so on so forth. My my position on this
is very clear. This is an internal
matter of the Iranian people and the
Iranian nation. It has nothing to do
with me. If the Iranian people are
apparently unhappy, let's say, then they
should take it up with their government.
We should not interfere in this matter.
It has nothing to do with us. But
remember, before the regime of the
ayatlas and the mulas, the current
regime, before that, you had the regime
of Shah Muhammad Razelvi,
a democratic Iran where women could wear
short skirts and everybody, nobody would
bother them. Great. But what was the
geopolitical out outlook? They supported
the US. They supported Pakistan
in 1965. They supported Pakistan in the
India Pakistan war 1965
and they were a US vasal.
Do you want
a situation where where even Persia is a
US? Right now you already have Pakistan
a US and Trump is going all out in favor
of Pakistan. Now imagine that problem
being magnified 10fold with with Porsche
also becoming a US facile.
Imagine that scenario. Do you want that
scenario to exist to to occur? I don't
understand this idiotic 30 IQ Indian
right-wingers who are jumping and
dancing that Israel has hit Iran. It
will be a disaster for India if there's
a regime change and a pro- US regime
comes to power in Iran. It will be an
absolutely absolutely unprecedented
disaster for India. So that is my
position on this. I would like the
regime of the moolas and the ayatas to
continue in Iran.
At least they they are not anti-India.
NTN 888 says sir prefers dictatorship
monarchy over democracy every dictator
state got bad rights censorship no media
freedom. Is this not worth high
development etc etc etc. Uh tell me
something sir ma'am whoever you are.
If you look look back at Indian history.
Yes. When was the last time we had
we had a great ruler in this country?
Possibly it was Chhatraatwaji Maharaj.
Last time we had a great ruler and
obviously the various Peshawas who came
after him. Tell me something.
Were they democratically elected by the
people of India?
Did they allow the people to vote
against them?
These were monarchs in other words
dictators.
Was Raj Rajola
democratically elected? And did he
transfer power to his son Rajendra Chola
democratic democratically after the
people voted for Raj Rajendra Chola?
What utter nonsense? This was a
dictatorship. Nobody dared question the
king the emperor.
What about
the great uh Kumar Gupta, Chandra Gupta,
Scand Gupta etc.
of the of the Gupta Empire were they
democratically elected did they transfer
power after getting the people's votes
but India did tremendously well during
the during these times right
what about Kaneshka the Kushal the great
one of the one of the greatest emperors
we've had was he a democratically
elected emperor what about Lord Krishna
when he was king of Dwara did the people
vote him to power
what about Lord Ram was he a
democratically elected uh leader. So
when his father Dashraat is handing over
the throne to his son, did he ask the
people for a vote? What are you people
dreaming of? And what are what what
world are you living in? We've always
had dictatorships in India
and it's always turned out well for
India. The current present system is is
is the problem and that's why we have
this this low standards all over the
place in India. And if even if you want
to change something, you can't. And you
see obvious problems that that are that
are terrible for India. A 100 million
Bangladesh is Rohingya's cookies and
Pakistanis in India. You think a
dictator would have tolerated that this
incredibly gigantic national security
threat?
So I would say you you know yeah you you
can sometimes have bad dictators like K
like Jalasand
like like uh Mahapad Manand etc. But as
long as the Indian monarchy is guided by
the constitution which is dharma it is a
very low chance of happening and so on.
So that's what I have to say about this.
Yes.
Uh really now says no concern about
Korean evation after Ju crash. Well
that's how it goes. Hardik Jooshi says
okay thank you so much. How safe is
anymore?
I don't mean fatally but things going
wrong in close calls. also thanks for
teaching how to think or instead of what
to think. Yeah, you're welcome. Um,
look, I think overall flying is safe. I
travel I I fly all the time and u day
before yesterday I was in an Air India
flight. Day before yesterday and day
before day before yesterday also I was
in an Air India flight.
Uh so look overall I think India is one
of the safest countries for flying
and I hope that what's happened this
this extremely sad thing that's happened
at least it will prompt a much deeper
scrutiny by the government of India and
the regulators etc into the aviation saf
safety standards and procedures and
protocols that we have in the country
which will obviously have the effect of
making flying even safer in India. So
overall I think we should not be
worried. We should not be scared.
Overall India is very safe. I think it's
safer than most countries and let's not
worry about it.
Okay. Literally officer K says once
again Israel is
uh full support sir full support right
Indians Indians love Israel. Let me show
you something. Indians love Israel
unconditionally.
Indians give full support sir to Israel
at all times. Right? Let me show you
something. Let me put something on the
screen.
And Indian right wingers are right now
dancing on the aisles because India
because Israel is a hit Iran. So this is
a tweet by the Israel Defense Forces.
Okay. Uh
aha ahuh. Now if they put it out after
after my tweet after my tweet see the
map of Isra India put out by our Israeli
friends. Oh, they've put out this map of
Iran being allegedly a global threat,
blah blah blah blah blah and so on. Now,
let's look at the map. Let's look at the
map of India. They've put out. They've
given Kashmir and much more to Pakistan.
This is something Israel does over and
over again. Once I pointed this out and
the Israeli ambassador had to apologize
and to pull the map down. The Israeli
ambassador had to apologize and pull the
map down after my tweet. But once again,
they are back at it, right? And oh oh oh
oh oh oh oh oh oh oh oh oh oh oh oh oh
oh oh oh oh oh oh oh oh oh oh oh oh they
have also showed Arunachal Pradesh is
part of China. Well well that's so nice
of our Israeli friends. That's so nice
of our Israeli friends. Let us see. Oh
yes Arunachal Pradesh is missing.
They have given Arunachal Pradesh to
China. They've given Kashmir and maybe
some part of Punjab also to to
Pakistan.
That's lovely. And there there is no
undermands for us apparently and so on.
So this is what Israel does. It's not
the first time the the Israelis have
done this. They do this over and over
again. But Indians will keep worshiping
Israel. I have nothing personal against
Israel by the way. Absolutely nothing.
There's a lot to admire in Israel about
what Israel does. But to to imagine that
they are some super friend of ours
and what world are you living in?
Yeah. So this is not a silly mistake.
This is a pattern. It's a pattern you
see over and over again with Israel,
especially when it comes to comes to the
maps of India.
So I don't know I I keep on pointing
this out but Indians will never learn.
Indians are I I don't know what to say
about Indians. So here we have it. Uh
Dr. Ritik Patnak says what if the look
what if what if the Axis powers won
World War II impact on India? Would
India become a vasal country under
German Japan with Subbash Bos's puppet
prime minister?
Look these what if scenarios you can
make any kind of story from a what what
if scenario. Of course you can do a
proper forecasting like I do in
geostrategy etc. But what is the point
is my question. What is the point of
exploring these fictitious scenarios
alternative history scenarios. What's
the point?
Yeah. So if the axis powers world one
were World War II maybe we would be
speaking in Deutscha.
and so on. Yeah.
And would India become vasal country
with Subash Boet PM? How dare you call
Subash Boet PM? How dare you?
Look, it's an exercise in futility.
What's the point? I don't get it. Maybe
he would be speaking German or maybe he
would be speaking Japanese. Yes,
Japanese
and so on. Uh Aries Manticor says in
case of World War II, do we stand alone
objectively or are we forced to treat
the whole world as potentially
adversarial? With neither side willing
to accept us, we focus on becoming a
silent third world power.
In the case of World War II, there's no
point of thinking anything because the
world will end. You people don't
understand what World War II means,
right?
World War II means the end of the world.
That's what it means. It means nuclear
exchange between the US and Russia.
That's what World War II means. There is
no standing aside. Everybody dies.
no taking sides and blah blah in World
War II. Once the nuclear exchange
happens, it's over. Over for everybody,
no matter where you are.
Okay. Basar says, "My question is in
this super chat comment." Well, I don't
see a question, but thank you for the 40
bucks, sir. What can I say? If you have
a question, please ask, right? What's
the point of this?
Uh, Geopol says, "Does I22 still exist?"
I think it still exists on paper and
maybe it will be taken up at some point
in time. The um Yeah, but um what is the
I2U2? It is the No, it's not the IP,
iMac, I2U2. It's India,
Israel, USA and uh UAE.
I think that's what I2 was and I think
it still exists but I'm not sure if if
there is work being done on that and if
I'm not sure if it's an active thing
that we engage in. So I think it pops up
from time to time but it's not something
that is active actively pursuing being
pursued right now. That's the guess.
That's the sense that I get because I've
not heard of I do YouTube for a while
and I'm not it's it's slipped past my
you know my mental horizon for some time
now.
Vicki says do you think Israel is our
friend seeing our map? Well you tell me.
Who am I to say? I can only show you the
map then. Now you people decide. You
people have a brain right? You people
are capable of thinking yes. Now do I
have to tell you do I have to chew the
food and then put in your mouth? Really?
You tell me Vicki
will a friend do that for to you.
You tell me.
Advatas sha back in Iran. What would it
mean for India? It means disaster for
India. It means a pro- US wasal back in
power in Persia. And pro- US means pro
Pakistan. Which means that both Pakistan
and Persia will be will be anti-India.
Do you want that? No, thank you.
Um really now says how come ancient
China had haram and slaves dharma.
China was not a dharmic nation as such.
The emperors never followed dharma. They
always followed confusionism.
They always followed legalistic
practices that started with hang
possibly. It's been a while since I read
Chinese history. So I may be a little
blurry on that. But the Chinese emperors
were never Buddhist. or Hindu whatever
they never practice that. It is the
Chinese people that practice that.
Chinese kings did become Buddhists and
they fought each other for the privilege
of of hosting one some of the Indian u
gurus who would travel to China. But the
emperors the top the top dog would never
be a Buddhist. There would always be
confusions. And in Confucianism there is
no god. There's no morality.
So there we have it. Sharma says, "Many
white men are really into Latinos.
A man being into a Latino instead of a
Latina."
Okay, whatever. Whatever rocks your
boat, guys. So many white men are really
into Latinos. And brown men are
notorious for being into white women.
Me. Okay. Sharma is into white women.
Good for you, bro. So are men hardwired
to seek out genetic diversity? I think
that could be Yeah. valid thing. Genetic
diversity makes sense. It it gives you
uh hardier offspring and so on.
So yeah, it it could be a genetically
hardwired thing that you well men are
genetically hardwired to be promiscuous
actually. Okay, that's that's a fact.
It's it's something you know from
historical evidence. What did the Yamaya
do? That's what they did. Kill all the
men and take all the women. That's
that's what the Turks did. That's what
the Arabs did. That's what every every
rapacious culture did.
So I think men are hardwired to do that
and and women are hardwired genetically
to do something different to settle with
one partner and uh when it comes to a
civilized existence I think the way of
the women wins because a partner that
gives you a stable society. Uh but what
you're saying makes sense. I think men
could be hardwired to seek out genetic
diversity. It makes sense from a genetic
perspective to have a partner that's way
more different than you genetically
which ensures that you will have very
hardy offspring with with good traits
from both sides. So yeah it makes sense
I think.
Okay Gro says aim in US news was fake
why was it spreaded he has not reached
the US who is saying that he's been
invited to go to the US I think he will
go there.
Parasi says why is India not focusing on
AI? Well, did you watch the Indian
interest
episode that I just did? We are super
focusing on AI. We're going to have
machine guns and all kinds of weapon
systems that will have AI integrated
into them. So, I think it's happening.
It's not all over the news. It's not
front page news and all, but India is
taking AI very very very very seriously
now. Trust me, it is. We are taking it
very seriously. Maybe not at the LLM
level and chat bots level, which is but
at the military level. And when you when
you do stuff at the military level, you
don't talk about it. Okay. So, so
Nan Chabra says, "Oh, Namj
Nam Chabra says, I think China having
Pakistan under its influence is a good
thing. That way,
India has to prepare for essentially the
same weapons in case of a war." No, it's
not necessarily a good thing. I mean, I
know what you're trying to say that
okay, we don't have to worry about this
weapon, that weapon system, etc. will
only have one set of weapon systems all
over the place. Uh but let's assume that
China has actually some some very
sophisticated weapons. Do you want them
to do you want the goddamn Pakistanis to
have those? Do you want them to have
those? Really? It's it's not a good
thing from that perspective. Um
but uh overall it's not something we can
control. So the Pakistanis we're going
to we'll see they're going to have a
mish mash of weapons. They will have
some Turkish weapons. They'll have some
American weapons. And then they're going
to have some Chinese weapons. Um, and
the Americans will keep helping them in
in a variety of ways. Uh, refurbishing
their F-16s, giving them uh, bailouts
from the IMF and the World Bank and
whatnot. And the Chinese will sell them
J35 fighter planes and various advanced
radar systems and whatnot. That's going
to continue. Uh but from the perspective
of imagining that the Pakistanis will
have only Chinese weapons, it's not
correct. They will also have Turkish
weapons. They'll also have American
weapons which actually makes it a
nightmare for India to to have to
contend with the possibility of all
these different kinds of weapon systems
being used simultaneously against us.
But we can take care of it for sure.
Tanmay Pant says communist historians
say that Delhi's sultanate Delhi's
sultenates Amir Khasra
is the person behind Hindi language or
Khariboli
isn't prat rasoproto Hindi see the Hindi
language or the Hindi language it is an
Indian language but unfortunately it has
been infused with all these foreign
words turic words and Arabic words so
many words I can tell you which are of
for example the word Hindi word mullayim
Main it means bland in Turkish. The word
the word which means I don't know
what some organ it means liver
in Turkish. The word tawa for that that
flat surface on which you cook. It's a
Turkish word
and there are so many Arabic words
across Hindi. So all Persian words also
I have no issue with Persian words
because it's a sister language, daughter
language of Sanskrit and so on. But all
of this happened because of of the
amalgamation of of the languages. So in
in the the the Turk courts would have
people who would speak local languages,
prait based languages
like protohindi etc. Proto Aawadi etc.
and and and there would be people
speaking Turk languages like Chagatai
etc. There will be people speaking
Persians of people speaking Arabic. So
all of this eventually got mixed up in
one single language. It evolved like a
mongrel language. So it has the
grammatical structure etc. and and lot
of vocabulary of a of a prait language
Sanskrit derived language abranch
language with lots of words that came
from other foreign languages.
Um but I would not say airro is behind
the Hindi language. I mean he wrote some
poetry in the Hindi of that time. If you
try to read it today you won't
understand a goddamn word of it. Right?
Um so communist historians will give all
kinds of credit to to to foreigners.
That's what they have always done. But
we don't need to take them seriously.
Ron Senpai says we see a pattern of that
Europe glorifies Egyptians even though
we have evidence of more complex
civilizations in the Amazon rainforest
in the civilization era of India and so
on. Why? I'll tell you why. The west
glorifies cultures they have destroyed.
Okay. They will only glorify those
cultures that they have destroyed. They
will glorify those cultures that they
have reduced to to specimens in a museum
or in a zoo.
A few months ago, maybe a year or so
ago, I watched this Marvel movie called
Multiverse of Misery. Multiverse of
Madness. Okay. In which there was this
scene, I think it's one of these Marvel
movies. I think it was multiverse of
whatever in which there's a scene in
which Thor they've depicted Thor as as a
loser alcoholic kind of person. Thor is
Indra by the way. Okay. So they've
depicted Thor going into a conference of
all the gods. All the gods in the world.
There are Polynesian gods and there are
Egyptian gods and there is there are
Scandinavian gods and Thor meets Zeus. I
mean are you people crazy? How can you
meet yourself? Thor is the the the
Nordic version of the Greek god Zeus.
Zeus Peter was Jupiter in Rome and Zeus
Peter was was named after Dors Petro a
Sanskrit name and that's the
representation of Indra. Anyhow all the
gods are represented over there in that
conference of of the gods Egyptian gods
and some obscure gods are there etc etc
but you will not see a single Indian god
there. Why? because they hate Indian
gods because we our gods are still free
and our culture is still not destroyed.
So they will extol the virtues of all
the cultures they have destroyed
but they will not do that for Indian
gods. Uh Amazon rainforest that's
another example but um they they
destroyed the cultures of the Amazon
region so thoroughly that nothing
survives. We don't even know the names
of their gods and so on. They destroyed
it so thoroughly. Spaniards. Ah, the
Spaniards were such utter barbarians.
Anyhow,
Sik Mundus says, "How far is the future?
All Indians are middle class or up and
have no more fear of Islam or Gazwa,
whatever. Take ASI into consideration."
Uh, listen, I do not answer questions
about religious strife, the Hindu Muslim
stuff and all that. I am not the guy for
that.
I'm not the guy for that. There are
other YouTube channels that that discuss
this threadbear. I do not discuss all
these religious strife issues, Hindus
fighting Muslims and the threat of this
religion and that religion what not.
That's not my cup of tea. I will discuss
history, geopolitic science. I should
actually put out a disclaimer today also
that I will only take questions about
history, geopolitic science, but I don't
I don't take up those questions. Okay?
So, apologies for that.
NCurit thank you very much sir thank you
here Kumar Patel says what mistakes made
by US what mistakes by by US made Russia
India China sovereign
that's not US mistakes Russia was always
sovereign uh China was also sovereign
they had a brief 100-year period in
which there was interference but overall
they were sovereign and uh the British
handing over power to a set of crooks in
India was nothing to do with the US at
the time the US did not have the power
to interfere here
So there you have it. Sergeant Skyan
says, "What should India do about the I
think India should develop the TEAS
program? Take it to its logical
conclusion. Right now we have we have
various versions future versions of the
TEAS that are being developed. The TEAS
should should form as should should
serve as the as the framework for a
whole set of aircraft families for the
future, right? Uh and the AMCA is going
to be an offshoot of that. All the
lessons that we have learned from the
development of the pages will be
incorporated into the AMCA development.
So it'll be much faster, much much
better and so on. And I think the I
think the the mark 1B or whatever mark 2
or whatever it is is going to come out.
We need to keep developing that. That's
what we should do.
Arismantic core has says that China has
been testing our patience for a long
time now. Should we as a country begin a
process to permanently decouple from the
China? China and US lobbies have long
molded us into subservient slaves. Our
bigger project problem when it comes to
mental colonization and molding Indians
into subservient slaves. The bigger
problem is not China. It is the west.
It is the west. It is the fact that we
all it is the the fact that we all speak
the English language and we see English
speaking culture as our culture. That's
the big problem. That's how we are so
badly influenced by the west.
And China is a much bigger power. So you
can't say they have been testing our
patience. As a much more powerful
nation, they will do what they want.
So the solution for us is is that we
should become as powerful as China,
eventually more powerful than China.
That's easier said than done. So
permanently decoupling from China, I
agree we should do that. I mean why are
we technologically dependent on China?
Why are we dependent on China for rare
earth minerals and and rare earth
magnets and so much more? It gives China
such a big leverage over us. Now they
have stopped supplies of rare earth
magnets and all that to India. We only
have supplies until mid July. After that
our our electric vehicle sector will
will shut down.
I don't understand why we have been so
shortsighted. So we need to permanently
decouple from China. We need to have
multiple sources of everything. We have
our own rare earth elements in India but
we have done nothing to extract them. So
we have been caught napping and it will
take us some time to decouple properly.
But you're right.
NC Punit says suppose Iran gets nukes
you know is fat in the world order but
it will significantly change the world
order Iran will not be that easy to
bully them
and overall it will kind of destabilize
the region to a certain extent it'll
cause tensions all over the place I
would like Iran to be safe and stable
and secure and I want it to continue to
exist the way it is right now but I
would not be a big fan of Iran getting
nukes
Then we would have two
um neighboring nations
that would have nukes. Three actually,
China, then Pakistan and also Iran is
going to significantly complicate
issues. So we don't want Iran to get
nukes, but Iran could could be in a
position right now where they may have
nukes. They probably have enough file
material for at least 10 nuclear
warheads, maybe more.
So
yeah, maybe it stabilizes the region.
Maybe it's good for Iran. It's
definitely good for Iran, I would say.
Um, Grock says, "Why US didn't do
something
Central Asia to capture rare earths?
The US doesn't belong in Central Asia.
Central Asia is a region where you have
which comes under Russia's sphere of
influence. Russia sees Central Asia as
part of its exclusive sphere of
influence.
The US have been interfering in Central
Asia for quite some time. You know,
there's an American University of
Central Asia in Bishkek, Kygythan
and so on so forth. But when it comes to
extracting resources, the Russians won't
allow that to happen. So,
uh, Ankita says, "What will be the fate
of Iran in the future according to my
analysis? Is it going to be transformed
into another South Korea as speculated
predicted by some experts? I would not
want to see that happen. I hope it
doesn't happen. Um,
okay, let's consider the scen consider
the scenarios. Let's say the Israelis
attack Iran and try to decapitate the
leadership. Iran will have no option but
to try and strike at Israel, which
starts a hot war in the region. Um, if
the Americans try to interfere, the Isra
the Iranians can hit every single
American air base and military base in
the region which starts a big
conflagration in the region. Big
regional conflagration and oil prices
skyrocket and it's a big mess all over
the world. We could be on the doorstep
of that scenario right now. Okay. But
then what happens? Can the US and Israel
come together to destroy Iran? It's
possible. You may even have a limited
nuclear exchange here.
Uh but if Iran they they decide they
will destroy Iran and they destroy Iran
and then they put up a puppet government
of some sha or something in place. If
that happens then it's it's terrible for
the region. So if Iran is to fall it
will probably lead to a nuclear exchange
limited nuclear exchange in the region
which would be horrible horrible.
I think that uh I hope that sane minds
will prevail.
But yeah, right now we are at a 50-50
position right now. If Israel continues
these strikes, I think Iran will respond
significantly very vigorously and then
you could be on the brink of allout war
and that all-out war could end with the
destruction of Iran and the and a regime
change in the region which would be
terrible geopolitically for the whole
region and it would be a disaster for
India as well. And if this happens then
they will convert Iran into another
vasal state like it used to be before
the ayatas came to power and then they
will say yeah then in that case Iran
could eventually become a South
Korea-like country slowly decaying and
being destroyed
and yeah but I hope it doesn't happen. I
hope it definitely doesn't happen. So
what is my prediction? I think it's too
early to predict. I think it's all 50/50
right now.
Aditya Ragul Ragul says talk about
Iranian Muslim families in Hyderabad
Bang Bangalore who don't look like
Indians more cockasoid that enjoy dual
citizenship a Ali Akar Miraa is other
mirazis
who migrated during 1800s 1900s I am not
aware of these people I don't I'm not
aware of this history
don't know there have been see I can
tell you this that lots of India and
Persia neighboring countries for the
longest time and there have been lots of
Persians who migrated to India and lots
of people Indians who possibly would
have migrated to Persia uh and so on. I
mean
Kmeni's ancestors were from Lacno I
think at least one of his ancestors
lived in Lacno for a significant period
of time and so on. So when you are
neighboring countries this sort of
exchange happens it's it's normal for
that to happen.
Um so that's what I can tell you. I'm
not aware of all these individuals that
you have named. That's not part of um my
focus in historical research. It's not
something I'm interested in. So, I won't
be able to answer in specifics about
this because I'm not aware of it.
Okay. Shivam Bakshi says, I understand
China is collapsing population wise, but
will they manage to maintain a growing
economy with AI and robotics? They will
try their best to do that. They'll try
their best. Uh see the population is
decreasing which means your population
is aging soon enough. You will have a
population that where the average median
age is in the 60s maybe 65. The average
person is 65 years old. Imagine that
everybody's old. So very few people are
having kids. That is a disaster. But
then you have technological superiority.
You're technologically very advanced. So
you can
marry AI and robotics and have robots do
all the work for you. So it doesn't
matter whether all your population
whether the majority of your population
is old people. Doesn't matter. But how
long can you ma maintain this economy
and all that? You can have the robots do
all the work for the people and you can
have robots fight wars. You can have
robot dogs and robot eagles and robot
whatever else is tyrannosaurus rexes
fighting wars for you. But eventually
what happens? Your population is going
to collapse and it's going to die out
possibly. Then what do you do with it?
So I think it's a long-term disaster
scenario for China actually, right? But
yeah, for the for the time being it's
it's a huge threat for India, China.
Until the end of the century, it's going
to be a big threat.
He's manticor says world war 2.5 could
be AI based before nuke exchange. Um no
AI based war that that is that's not
world war 2.5. The next world war is
going to have if it happens it it could
end up in a nuclear exchange which will
disrupt the world. And you already have
AI systems being used in warfare. Uh
many of the drones could be autonomous
and so on. You know the anti-personnel
drones that you are seeing in in the
Ukraine conflict. Many of these are
autonomous drones. So you already have
AI uh that's participating in warfare.
So that's not world war world war 2.5 or
anything. So yeah,
kapay developer kapay developer says P
crash of plane past 10 years data minus
okay it's of the order of 0.008
uh the probability of VVIP and
commercial plane etc etc etc.
VVIP well I would not call Mr. Rupani a
VVIP he is a former chief minister
um but I know what you're trying to say
so the probability of both the events
happening of of both independent happen
events happening simultaneously is of
the order of 1.6 6 * 10 - 8 which is
astronomically
minuscule.
Interesting. So I know what you're
trying to hint but let's not get into
the territory at this point in time.
You're trying to hint that there could
be sabotage or something but I think
it's too early for us to reach such
conclusions even though what you're
showing over here well I don't think
they can be denied.
Sarang says grateful. Okay. Thank you so
much sir. Thank you very much. Uh okay.
All you are saying you don't have a
question. Well well thank you so much. I
really appreciate it. I really
appreciate uh the contribution and the
very very kind words and I appreciate
your viewership. Thank you so much. It
really means a lot. Thank you.
Barata says Vedas describes Sarasati in
its grandest form. Multip disciplinary
science studies hint at a grand river.
They don't hint. They've demonstrated
there was a grand river in northwest
India only about 9 to 18,000 years
before. Today good coro corroboration
for some Vic mandelas being that old let
me show you what the deal is the Vedas
the rig Va let's not talk about all the
Vedas let's talk about the riga the
rigida talks about the sarasvati in its
grandest form if you want to know what
it says let's go to Google
okay let's go to Google
invasion mit shavda
So, where is it? Where where is it? Um,
what what
Okay, I should just quickly go to the
first link. medium.com. This is an
article of by me from 2017. So, where is
where is Saraswati?
Saraswati. Saraswati. Um,
Saraswati.
Okay. The Saraspati river is extensively
mentioned in the Rigida, India's
foundational literary text. It is
referred to as the greatest of rivers.
Glorious, loudly roaring in the mother
of floods. This clearly refers to a
mighty river in its prime, not a river
in decline. This falsifies the Arian
invasion theory account that the rigida
was composed after a perpetated arian
invasion of migration circa 1500 BC
and indicates it was composed closer to
5,000 BC when the river was last in its
prime per the results of this study that
I've mentioned about that I've mentioned
circar a
uh and so on okay so the point is
that the river the great Sarasbati was
last in her prime came around 5,000
6,000 BC about 8,000 years before today
and that's the point at which the Indian
rainy season the monsoon starts
declining slowly gradually monotonically
and eventually it declines to such an
extent that by about 1500 AD uh BC by
about 1500 BC the Sarasati is largely
dried out it's made a huge puddle which
is now the run of Kutch and and so on
and eventually also the Tar desert
so the river was last inner prime around
8,000 BC. It indicates that the rig
weather was composed closer to 8,000 BC
than to 1500 BC
and I it doesn't mean that it was
composed 18,000 BC. Okay, you you can't
extrapolate that sort of thing. So my
what I can say is that it was composed
closer to 8,000 BC than 2500 BC. Beyond
that I cannot say anything else.
So I would not go in and venture that
maybe the rigida was written at 18,000
years before today. That is I think
perhaps stretching it too far and that
would be well it could equally well have
been written at around 6,000 BC or 7,000
BC. But what's clear is that it's the
world's oldest literary text. No
question about that.
Kavia says
Christian missionaries are targeting
Indian states like Kerala Tamil Nadu and
northeast state for conversion after
independence. They did that. Yeah. After
independence. Uh why were these states
targeted as they were less affected by
Mughal brutality.
Why did they target these states? For
example, the far eastern states,
northeast states, Nagaland etc. These
were remote states where people lived in
the hills and all that tribal
populations. Tribal populations have
historically been far easier to convert
to Christianity than populations that
are not tribal and not nomadic.
uh also you will find that populations
that are uh in poverty are easier to
convert by Christian missionaries just
by offering rice bags. The Chinese and
the Japanese wrote about this.
The Chinese in the 1800s wrote about
rice Christians.
So the Christian missionaries, the
American British Christian missionaries
would have this practice in China. They
would create conditions for famines in
China and then they would offer bags of
rice to Chinese peasants as inducements
to convert to Christianity.
The condition was that we'll offer you
this bag of rice but we will offer you
only if you convert to Christianity.
So you were not being made to convert of
your own free will. It was a inducement.
You had no choice otherwise you die. So
that's the tactics these people have
historically used. And in India, the
British created horrible famines and
horrible poverty and the Nuvian regime
took a long long time to do anything
about these things. So it was so easy to
convert poor people to Christianity,
people who were starving and so on. And
maybe Kerala, Tamil Nadu, maybe all of
these places, they already had certain
issues there. That's why it was easier
to start over there.
Um
yeah. So I I'm I'm not sure if there's a
connection with Mughal brutality, but
yeah, that's how historically the
pattern has been.
Vic post says any good book or source on
raw training. You will find no books on
raw training. These things are not to be
written in books.
But if you want to read nasty stuff,
read the CIA field manuals, etc.
CIA field manuals, PDFs from the 1970s
and 80s from the time that they were
running all their operations in Latin
America and so on. Very nasty stuff.
Uh
Vidi says, "Does Israel missow India's
map to signal the US?" Nah, they don't
have to signal anything to the US.
Absolutely not. They're signaling
something to us and to the rest of the
world. They don't have to signal
anything to the US.
Okay. Cancer says US is crooked. Was the
USSR also like that before? Big fan.
Thank you, sir. Every big power is going
to act hypocritically. They're going to
say one thing, do another. They're going
to always prioritize their own
interests. It's never going to be about
what's right, what's wrong, but what's
best for me. So, the USSR also did such
things. No question about it. But
overall for India, the Russians were
always better. They were always more
reliable. So that's how it was
historically.
Strike 47 says, "What are your views on
Israel then? I'm unsure of how to
perceive their relationship with India.
From what I have seen, they've always
been loving loving
and I have so many Jewish friends. Why
do they show wrong map?" Okay. Okay.
Okay. Look, personal relationships have
nothing to do with in geopolitical
relationships. Please, Indians, why are
Indians so naive?
You go to the US, you will find so many
Pakistani taxi drivers who are so nice,
very pleasant to talk to, and they'll
become friends of yours. You go to
various restaurants, etc., you will find
Pakistanis all over the place.
They'll be very nice people. You go and
live in London, you will have many
Pakistani neighbors.
Especially those who settled down in the
20th century, they'll be nice, really
nice and very cordial and very well
behaved and all. Does it mean Pakistan
loves India? Because these people are
nice to you.
I
personal experience and interpersonal
relationships have nothing to do with
nationto-nation relationships.
Absolutely nothing. Now, look at it this
way. If you watch yesterday's live
stream that I did, episode 5 of Geost
Strategy, you will see why Trump love
loves Pakistan so much
because he is in the process of
investing about 65
he's in the process of investing lots of
money in Pakistan and there is about $65
trillion worth of of resources to be
extracted out of Pakistan. So Pakistan
is willing to give up their their
resources to Trump for plundering and
that's why Trump loves Pakistan so much.
Now Trump loves Israel very much. Trump
is a huge supporter of Israel and the US
is Israel's number one ally
and Israel's
Israel is also the US's number one ally.
So it's a mutual partnership these two
nations have. So Israel and US are each
other's number one ally.
US has a top vasal
in the Indian subcontinent which is
Pakistan.
So if US is favorably inclined towards
Pakistan and Israel and US have this
alliance of number one ally then the
question is what is Israel's
relationship with Pakistan?
They don't have diplomatic relations
but have you seen Israel ever do a thing
against Pakistan?
They will talk.
Talk talk is cheap.
I want to see actions. What actions?
Give me give me an example of some hard
actions Israel has taken in the past
about Pakistan against Pakistan.
I'll wait. I'll wait forever.
Right
now, Israel has been very good for
India. We have a good strategic
partnership. Right. Uh we have various
defense agreements. We we are developing
various technologies jointly and all. So
it's great it's a great partnership
overall but Israel has this history of
showing the wrong Indian map. There's
also the question of Manipur.
A large number of of cookies cookie
infiltrators have become Israeli
citizens by claiming to be of Jewish
origin when there is 0% Jewish DNA in
these people and they love eating pork.
But they have succeeded in becoming
Israeli citizens. And Israel had this
had this conversion program going on in
which they would officially baptize or
whatever it is the Israeli the Jewish
religion does to make someone officially
Jewish and they have brought in a lot of
cookies who are now living in is in
Israel
and these cookies who are now Israeli
citizens are have been caught supporting
the the cookie terrorism in Manipur
and recently I know that the Israelis
had had had brought in some Indian
influencers to Israel on a tour of
Israel. Okay. And they had these Indian
influencers meet a cookie rabbi to talk
about Manipur. Now that's direct
government interference in Indian Indian
affairs. Indian internal affairs,
right? A cookie rabbi was brought to
meet the Indian influencers and and talk
about Manipur. Who the hell is that
cookie Israeli rabbi to talk about
Manipur? What business does he have
doing it? So there are many issues in
the India Israel relationship. Overall
it's a great relationship but there are
issues. So my friends, you may have a
couple of Jewish friends. I'm sure you
have good relations with them. It
doesn't mean that everything is great.
Of course, India also doesn't always
vote vote in favor of Israel when it
comes to various resolutions. India
typically abstains or or votes against
Israel when it comes to various
resolutions in the UN about Palestine
and so on so forth. So you to understand
it's a complicated relationship. It's
not all all all love and happiness and
all that full supports are like Indians
do. Indians
what can I say that's so incredibly
immature.
Uh and so that that's the deal. That's
what I can tell you. Rahul Ladu says
make in India didn't succeed as much as
we expected. What policies should India
imp implement now? Rephrase.
Make in India is working. It it takes
time. There are lots of problems in
India, lots of internal problems. But we
cannot say it did not succeed because
until today it's not brought all all the
results that we wanted. We're going to
keep on persevering. We're going to make
it work.
Right? So what policies should India
implement? We should make it easier to
do business in India. First of all, it
is pretty difficult even for Indians to
to do to conduct business in India. All
kinds of regulatory roadblocks and red
tape and allegedly corruption allegedly
etc. Right? Land acquisition is such a
problem. If you are a foreign company or
a foreign entity or investor, you want
to invest in India and if you want to
acquire land, it's a nightmare for you.
You go to China, they will roll out the
red carpet for you as if you're a VI
VVIP. In India, they they will ask you
to fill up 78 forms in triplicate. So
all these things need to be dealt with,
right? So if you do all of this stuff,
then it'll be easier for foreigners and
etc people to invest in India. And
that's one of the big things we need to
do.
Kapay developer says, "How does one
counter leverage both from an individual
and national perspective standpoint?"
You counter leverage by having leverage
by developing leverage of your own.
So that's what you do. So for example,
what leverage does the US have over
India? They have East Pakistan and West
Pakistan. Both are their vasals. They
have other nations that also belong to
them. They have unleashed mayhem in
Manipur via via uh via Myanmar because
they are running a proxy civil war in
Myanmar. So they have so many points of
leverage on India. So what can India do
about this? Now India doesn't have the
leverage right now of running similar
operations in the US backyard. It's not
possible, right? So but if India wants
to counter this, then India needs to
become more powerful such that we can
also do such things to the US. Then they
will behave.
So when it comes to China, okay, the
Americans have imposed all kinds of
tariffs on the Chinese. So that's the
leverage they have over the Chinese,
right? So how did the Chinese respond?
They have restricted exports of rare
earth minerals and magnets and all that
to the US. Then they control about 95%
of the world's supply. That's a huge
leverage they have and that's why the
Americans have brought the Chinese to
the to the negotiating table. They said,
"Okay, you have leverage now. We need to
find a solution." Now the Chinese have
imposed these restrictions on India also
but India doesn't have leverage over
China. So what you have to do is you
have to develop your own leverage over
other countries. If you become a much
much larger market that everybody needs
and that's a leverage you have over
others. If you have a massive navy then
you can bully other nations by saying
that look my navy will turn up to
tomorrow tomorrow morning at your
doorstep with these many aircraft and
these many soldiers then what will you
do and so on. So you have to develop
your own different ways of applying
leverage on other countries. That's what
you do. That's from a national
perspective. Now you can bring it down
to the individual perspective also. So
that's what you do. Sir
MK says, what would the what could the
UK have done differently to remain as an
empire superpower? Second, what was
responsible for Germany becoming a
technological power in the 20th century?
What was the cause for Germany becoming
such a technological power in the 20th
century? Educational reforms.
They completely revamped. First of all,
in 1871, this artificial new nation of
Germany was created for the first time
ever. Before that, there was no Germany
ever.
Then they wanted to become a massive
European power. So they created the kind
of education system that was focused on
science and research and technology and
they made it completely meritocratic and
they they they ensured that the system
produces identifies the best talent and
rewards the best talent and they also
became a major industrial level uh
industrial nation because of which you
would need to source the best uh
brightest talent from the education
system. So all of that caused this great
technological blooming in Germany and
that's why it become a great
technological power. The roots go the
roots of this success lie in the 19th
century. What could the UK have done
differently to remain as an empire
superpower? Um they should have ensured
that Germany did not doesn't rise.
That's one thing they could have done
and many other things like uh
yeah at the end of the day they were
overstretched and the US suddenly
emerged as this great power and there's
nothing they could have done to prevent
that. So I think the UK's time was done
essentially. He's manticor says speaking
of unofficial foreign lobbies in India
isn't it suspicious that bureaucrats of
DRO and HOL keep messing up projects and
deals into 2014
even after which it could took 10 years
to straighten up. Well if there is any
such thing it would be kept under wraps.
It would be classified information.
Um so I can't really comment much about
that but you know what it's true that
we've had so many problems
and the current government of Mr. Modi
has has probably had to take years more
than a decade to straighten things. I'm
sure they still in the process of
straightening straightening out various
things and I'm sure there still is a lot
of foreign influence within India in
various ways. Okay. But I am not aware
of any specifics. So I cannot say speak
about that. I cannot comment about that.
Rahul says since
making India did not succeed as much as
we expected. What policies should India
implement now? I think I answered your
question.
I answered your question that India
needs to implement various
reforms
which will make it easier to do business
in India which will make it easier to
have contracts enforced. which will make
it easier to acquire land in India which
will make it less cumbersome a process
to to set up a company and and run a
company there should be red less red
tape there should be less alleged
corruption and so on so forth these are
the things India needs to do okay
Krishna thank you very much sir
Hersa says as innocent simp simple men's
slashed like vegetables in today's time
should men convert their personality to
alpha what's your thoughts experience
You can't change your personality. You
you have the personality you were born
with. Um today's world in India
especially is terrible. The laws are all
biased against men and men are
victimized. No question about it. That's
true. It's true. So what should men do?
Well, you have to be careful. You have
to be careful you don't get exploited.
You have to do your due diligence when
marrying somebody. Today the old system
of getting married has been thrown out
right especially in big cities you just
find some girl and you get fall in love
with her and you marry her and then very
often you may have to face certain
consequences in the past the the
families used to do the due diligence
about the the anticcedence of the person
you are
proposing to get married to. So they
would look into the person they would
look into the person's family they would
look into the person's ancestry and see
the kind of behavioral traits they've
demonstrated over time. That gives you a
very solid idea of what kind of person
this this could be and so on. It's gone
now. So that's a problem. What should
you do today? You should be as careful
as possible. But you can't really change
your personality. That's faking it. You
won't be able to fake it forever.
Krishna says, "Is Iran with a with
nuclear weapons a threat to India?"
That's always a possibility. Any nation
in the neighborhood with nuclear weapons
could be a threat. Which is why it will
be best for us to have a world in which
Iran doesn't have nuclear weapons.
Mayang says in USA Hindus are rich class
why don't they use their wealth to
counter anti-India anti-Hindu sentiments
by using their wealth because Hindus by
nature are not a political politically
oriented people
Hindus don't unite the way the
Abrahamics unite Hindus are very
different from each other I mean you
take 10 Hindus they'll be as different
from each other as as as you know any
other people in the world um so it's
never been the nature of Hindus to unite
politically
and Hindus have so many differences
different they have different kinds of
cuisines they have different kinds of
lifestyles they have different kinds of
languages they have different approaches
and attitudes to life and so on so forth
so the Hindus are very different it's a
very diverse country we live in that's
why it's so hard for Hindus to unite and
that's why Hindus don't unite outside of
India
inferno JS says Trump versus Biden who
is the lesser of two evils for India
looks like Biden was the lesser of the
two evils doesn't It look like that
today. It does.
Uh Putin's ideology says cancer. Is he a
communist? Does Russia Russia love
Lenin? Putin is not a communist. Putin
is a nationalist.
I don't think he's a big fan of Lenin.
Uh but he loves Russia and he's a big
nationalist.
Um, Sergeant Skylin says, "Lol, did
Purfam not meet with Rama regarding the
same gods not being able to meet with
each other?" Yeah, I am not aware of
that's this is not my cup of tea. Who
did meet whom and all? Um,
was Perfuram an incarnation of Lord
Vishnu? Apparently,
did he meet Rama? Okay. Well, this is
for you guys to discuss, okay? This is
not for me. I'm not taking these
questions. Valika says, "Vadika, what a
nice name. If they would have shown a
Hindu god in the Thor movie, Indians
would have gone crazy and some
controversy would have happened." Well,
that's also true. Indians love
controversies. Indian love Indians love
to to be upset about things. Indians
love to Yeah, I'm sure Indians would
have protested that you do not show or
god right. You are right about that.
Proud Udia says, "Can Balo get free now?
US wants its resources." We'll see.
We'll see. I've seen you somewhere. Um,
if the US wants Baloi resources,
Balojasthan will not be free for the
next 1,00 years. So,
Sony says, "Suppose you want us to give,
suppose you want to give us five habits
for raising our standards long-term.
What will it be?" Um, physical fitness.
You need to have a physical fitness
routine. Lifting weights, not just
walking and running. Okay. Walking is
great. Walk a thousand 10,000 steps a
day like they say. But you need to lift
weights like three, four times a week at
least and get get strong. That's one.
Eat good food. Don't eat food that was
that did not exist a thousand years ago.
I'm I'm saying but even I do that. But
okay. Um so good diet. What else?
Pranayam and yoga is great.
So that's number three. Um
read
read and think. Don't read what's in
your curriculum. the curriculum books
will will rot your brain. Read books
beyond that. I know it's tedious. It's
time consuming. It's it hurts your mind
to read. But read, please read. And
fifth, I would say
u make money.
Find ways of making money. Making money
is good. It's not bad. It's not evil.
Indians hate somebody making money. But
I would say go and make money and get
rich. Get as rich as possible and use it
for for something good for society. So
that's perhaps five things you could do.
Jurgen says why the US and Israel
allowed Pakistan to have nuclear
weapons. They didn't they know that
Pakistan is an unreliable asset against
India. Pakistan is bad for India. That's
why they allowed this to happen. The
Israelis had this plan. They had this
plan with India of destroying the
Pakistani nuclear reactor sometime in
the 1980s. But the last moment the
Israelis pulled out of it. And I now
believe that the Pakistanis actually
have US nuclear bombs. I don't think the
Pakistanis have the IQ to develop
nuclear warheads of their own. Okay, you
can see what they've done with other
technologies. They don't have the brains
to do it. I think the Americans gave
Pakistan American nuclear warheads. I
think that's what the the Pakistanis
have.
Uh Ashish Shakespe says, "What would
happen to the world if Abraham Lincoln
were alive today? How might the world be
different? Many consider him to be the
one of the greatest presidents." Please
understand one thing. Abraham Lincoln
was not some kind of saint.
Read his life history and read some of
the nasty things he did. How many Native
Americans did he string up
because they were they were brown and so
on. But he was good for the US. You know
the the the American South seceded from
the union.
Do you know that the American South
seceded democratically from the union of
the United States?
They opted to partition the country and
create a separate country and they did
this democratically
and Abraham Lincoln acted
undemocratically by invading the south
and starting the civil war.
Please
don't just absorb
whatever you are to taught without
thinking.
And now people will say that I'm trying
to revise history.
Everybody loves somebody who just
conforms with all the accepted so-called
knowledge and wisdom. I am not one of
those people.
You have to look at the world
critically. What does it mean to to look
at the world critically? It means that
you have to question everything.
Only then can you actually find truth in
the world. Otherwise, you will only
absorb lies. Abraham Lincoln did nasty
things also. But of course, without him,
the US would not exist in the shape and
format that it does today. That's why
they consider him to be the one of the
greatest presidents but he was not a
saint
and so on. So what would happen if the
if he was alive today? Maybe the US will
act exactly the way it's acting right
now.
Arismanticor says some US experts claim
Christianity is spreading silently in
Iran. Experts which experts isn't it?
Atheism is there any basis for this?
What should Iran do to avoid South
Korea's fate? Iran should go back to
Zoroastrianism.
you know, Iran should ensure that it
doesn't become a US vasal. Otherwise, it
will end up in the same way that South
Korea is ending up right now.
Um, I don't know about this Christianity
thing. I I'm aware that of the claims
that there is atheism that's spreading
in Iran. Many Iranians want to go back
to the roots, but they don't know how
to. So, maybe India can help with that
perhaps or not. We'll see. Uh, but I am
not aware of what the real truth is
inside Iran.
Abishek says, "Was Nehu's power transfer
a smart move knowing that India was weak
and the West had nukes?
Had Moses's path worked? Could India
have been a target?" So you're saying
that, you know, keeping your head down
and remaining weak is a smart move.
Which west had nukes? Only the US had
nukes?
Only the US had nukes right at that
point in time. And if Moses' path would
have worked, then India would have been
a powerful country in a few years. Of
course, that would possibly have made
India a target. But if India if India
then played its game well, if if India
played its card right, then India could
have been multi-aligned instead of
becoming a US Vasal or or a US vasal.
So transferring power to a person who is
going to take your country down the road
of weakness is never a smart move.
Never.
Okay, I don't know how to read this
name. Uh, in my opinion, this thing
between Iran and Israel was long
expected. How do you think we should
move in this game? Um, kudos to the PRC
as the US will use their great ally and
self-service perceived slave
as a ground staging ground against Iran.
What's the question? How do you think we
should move in this game? India should
stay out of this game.
This doesn't concern India. Of course,
if is if Iran gets destroyed, it does
concern India. But India is in no
position to get involved in this matter.
So it's very simple. What should India's
position be in this? India should urge
both sides to go to the negotiating
table and stop fighting. This is not a
time for war. This is this is what we
should tell Iran and Israel.
But we are in no position to get
involved in this matter. So we should
stay out of it and we should urge
peace. We should urge restraint. That's
what our position position should be.
Hardik says what mistakes is India
making economically, politically and
culturally right now despite the the
economic rise. Culturally what we the
mistake we making look economically,
politically, culturally I can't answer
the same time. I'll take the cultural
question.
What India should do is reform the
education system so that the quality of
the Indian population rises. The mental
quality, the the critical thinking
ability, all of that. Right now, our
population is a bunch of sheep who don't
think but who think they know
everything.
We need to reform the education system
and we need to bring our culture back in
the forefront in in the thick of things.
Right now, we are a secular nation,
right? It's a disaster for India. It's
killing our culture.
The education system needs to be
reformed so that we teach our culture to
our children, our children. We need to
stop emphasizing foreign languages. We
should have our education only in our
mother tongue. We should make Sanskrit
the national language of India, the
civilizational language of India. The
primary the the main language of
education should be Sanskrit and the
mother tongue should also be taught and
English should not be taught otherwise
you'll end up like me who who a person
who can speak better in a foreign
language than in our own languages. So
that's one thing we should do and
there's so much more that needs to
happen. Uh culturally we need to become
you know we need to decolonize and
that's a whole big thing I can't answer
in in two three minutes or five minutes
but yeah start with the education system
it needs to be reformed and nothing is
being done right now which is very
disappointing.
Shiva Rajput says why doesn't India use
strong narrative warfare like Israel
especially when Pakistan openly burns
frags of India US and Israel threaten
our security etc etc all that yeah we
can certainly use more strong narrative
warfare like isra
struck at at Iran and then put out
proper well-crafted well narrated uh
perspective on Twitter and social media
all that we tend to like these big
conference rooms with where and there
was also quite effective our our
generals and and uh you know military
leaders putting out the thing but it
makes sense to go on a on social media
and do a social media PR blitz that's
something we can learn from Israel for
sure so I agree with you sir anonymous
says I'm doing well sir thank you I hope
you're doing well also should we patent
our inventions or not since there's a
chance they could be copied best way to
preserve inventions well I haven't
invented anything as such I am a
theoretician not a practical guy so I
don't know but you It makes sense to
patent your inventions. Otherwise,
people will copy them. You know, the
world is full of plagiarists
and if you make something good, the
chances are 100% that the moment
somebody sees it, they'll copy it. So,
the best thing is to patent all your
inventions and if somebody still copies
it, take them to court. That's it.
Nikl says, "Your thoughts if is the
recent German defense budget push is it
more aimed towards securing its own
position in Europe than to fight with an
external enemy?"
I think there's an element of both. So,
Germany has historically been the engine
that drives the European economy and has
historically been the major
European military power. Now after 1945
things went very sideways for Germany
and it became occupied by the US and
it's still being kind of in the center
of things economically and militarily
for NATO and the EU. So this defense
budget push could be aimed at kind of
towards restoring its old position as
the Reich that was at the center of
Europe. Yes. And u also if you have the
spectre of an external enemy then you it
helps you bolster your case for a
budgetary hike. And as it's actually
Trump who is pushing pushing for a
budgetary hike military budget hike for
the European nations. No more freebies
for you guys. Your budgets were used to
be in in used to be less than 2% of your
GDP. Now it has to be 5% of your GDP. So
maybe the whole of Europe is going in
that direction now. But yeah, there
there could be some element of what
you're saying over here.
Okay, I'm going to end this in a few
minutes now. So, please stop asking more
super chat questions. Please stop it.
Okay, I'm going to take whatever is
there and nothing more. So, it's ending
soon. US has been harping about China
doing aggro terrorism. Was there any
instance of a measured aggro terrorism
terrorism being done on India by
Pakistan and its impact? I am not aware
of any agot terrorism as far as I know
done by Pakistan on India. That's an
interesting question because
because it's something that can
certainly be attempted by Pakistan but I
have not researched this and I'm not
aware of any such instances. If there
are such instances and somebody knows
about it, please put it in the comments
below.
Shubam says, why is it that India is
often criticized for his actions while
Israel taking even bolder steps faces
little or no backlash? Isn't this clear
double standards? Indians love to
complain complain about double
standards. The world is filled with
hypocrisy in double standards.
Of course, you are right. Of course,
it's clear double standards. And that is
exactly the way the way the world works
through double standards. Rules for you
but not for me. That's how it works. So
why is Israel never criticized? Because
it is it is the primary number one ally
of the US.
And it is run by white folks. It has a
majority brown population, but it is run
by white folks, Israel.
And we are a nation of brownskinned
people. So we get criticized and they
don't double standards, but that's the
way the world works.
Vive says, "Are there more lost cities
like Dwara?" Thoughts? Thoughts? I can
give you facts. Kavari Pumatnam
on the east coast of India near
Pondicherry
at a at a depth of about 100 meters
below the ocean they have discovered the
city it is most likely the ancient
Kavari Pumatam of the Sangam era and
there's many more like these on the east
coast on the west coast there's a whole
gulf of Kamat archaeological complex a
network of sunken cities
at a depth below the sea level such that
the cities were last above sea level at
least 10 12,000 years before today and
the cities are laid out in a grid
structure like Manhattan
goosebumps yes
uh Vamshi Kalam says we are not a major
power hypocrite though we are not a
major power yet so that's why we are not
a hypocrite nation see we are not a
major power
there are only three major powers the US
China and Russia
we are not comparable to these three
nations right now and that's why we are
not in a position to be hypocritical.
Hypocr being see the ability to be a
hypocrite is a privilege that comes with
power. We still don't have that much
power. We are we are a rising power for
sure. We're the fourth most powerful
nation but we are like China is about
three times three and a half times more
powerful than us right now. So
okay B Mandav says we say that all
knowledge was stolen from India and
westerners use that knowledge to advance
them. Why can't we use the knowledge now
to advance ourselves or this is a lie?
See we should use all this knowledge to
advance ourselves. All the knowledge of
the world is available essentially for
free online.
Right? So why can't we reacquire all the
knowledge and use it to advance
ourselves? because that takes hard work
and for that you need a good system
and so on. So it is not the fault of the
Indian citizens, it's the fault of the
Indian government if things are not
going well and if we are still lagging
behind in certain sectors.
So yeah that's what I can say. It's not
a lie. It's not a lie at all. All the
knowledge was stolen from us. It has
been digested and now they are teaching
the same knowledge to us.
There is something called pranayam.
You know what the west calls it? They
call it either cardiac coherence
breathing or box breathing. and they put
it on Twitter and and X and social media
as if it's something they have invented.
So they have stolen the knowledge,
they've digested it and now they're
repackaging it and rebranding it in
different ways and they're presenting it
as their own invention. So that is not a
lie. It's absolutely true. The point is
if we want to stay ahead of everybody,
we have to create more knowledge. For
that we need a good education system
which is not there. So it's all the
fault of the government of India.
Abininov says
sorry no Brashan Kumar says Indians are
naive and soft so they become easy
target being naive makes you the best
target in the world Indians are super
naive what the way the world works
full support sir full support so easy to
fool you if you have that attitude full
support for whoever so yeah that's why
it's so easy to target Indians uh
aismantic horses Europe is being slowly
consumed by illegal migrants. It if it
reaches an extreme will the Christians
do another crusade or which trials will
the Vatican relocate and this should be
the neo neo Euro tribe war.
I think the Vatican will relocate to
India. They are trying their best to
completely convert India. Right? There
are industrial scale mass conversions
happening in Punjab in various other
parts of India. The government is is
acting like like what's her name?
Gandhari. I selectively blind. Right? So
the Vatican I think they they they are
losing Europe. The Europeans have are
done with Christianity. So the Vatican
wants to relocate to India. Maybe by
2100 the Vatican church will be based
somewhere in India and our descendants
will be doing all that whatever that is.
Vic post says is Mossad and CIA better
than RAW
from outside? How do I know sir?
How do I know? I am not a member of
either of these organizations. So I
don't know how they work. And if I was
in one of these three organizations,
then I would have intelligence about the
other two. But I am not. So I I cannot
answer the question. Okay? I know that
you would love me to say
or or raw is better than there are all
these Indian YouTubers who do that. I am
not one of those.
My answer is very simple. I don't know.
Okay. Lak Lakshi Akil says, "I am fond
of Arabian civilizations, especially
Petra, the world wonder, and Hegra built
by Bedwin, Nabbachian Arabs, early
Arabic speakers and ancestors of
northern Saudis and Jordanians. Do you
know that these were polytheistic
cultures that built all this?
Do you know that? You know that?" Yeah.
They have wonderful architecture. Petra
is beautiful. Of course, they say don't
be there at night because apparently
stuff happens
and so on. The Arabs had wonderful
culture. Even now, many of the Arabs
have wonderful culture and so on. You
have to be open-minded.
I think there are lots of wonderfully
nice Arabs in the world. Okay. And I
think India and Arab and the Arabic
countries are building a very good set
of relationships. So and so on. So yeah,
you're right. Petra is wonderful. Hegra,
I'm not sure but okay, I'll check it
out.
Okay, Vidi says, "What is Israel trying
to signal to India by mis showing
India's map? India, Israel is telling
India that you know what you guys don't
vote for us in the United Nations
sometimes. Sometimes you vote against
us, so we will do this stuff to you. You
are naughty, we will also be naughty."
Uh VS says, "Please explain why the F-35
aircraft is a useless piece of crap.
Also, do you know any books to
understand US deep state or MIC?
Read the devil's chessboard.
Okay, read that. The devil's chessboard
by by forget the name. That's one book
you can read which is very interesting.
It's about the threeletter agencies of
the US. Why is the F35 aircraft a
useless piece of crap? They spent so
much money to make it. It was delayed
over and over and over again. it it off
over overshot all of its um constraints,
all of the budgets or and they still
could not make it work and it is it is o
overly large. It doesn't have a good
radar cross-section apparently and it
crashes all too often and so on. So
overall, it's not a good it's not a good
plane. The F22 Raptor is probably the
best plane in the world.
The real high quality plane they have is
the F-22 Raptor. The F95 is crap. The
F-22 is is a piece of art. It's a work
of art and they don't export it to
anybody no matter how much you're
willing to pay. The F-22 is the real
deal, not the F35 garbage. Uh Dwanch
says on the your views on the death of
Robert Clive amassed great riches
through corruption, became the world's
richest guy. Then his slit his thought,
mother of suicide, a man who conquered a
lot of India. How did he do that? Can he
do that? I haven't studied Robert
Clive's history, life history. The the
past 1,000 years of Indian history. I
haven't studied it in great depth
because it is a history of misery and
foreign occupation and I have never been
interested in individuals like Robert
Cly. I have rather preferred to study
world history. So yeah, see recent
recent Indian history is not my forte.
The history of the Indian freedom
struggle and the history of Mr. Gandhi
and Mr. Ambedkar and Mr. Nu and the
details of their lives and Clive and all
not not my thing. Sorry.
Uh what's the process of denuclearizing
a country? First we do regime change.
You install a regime that is a puppet of
yours and then you get the nukes. That's
the the process of denuclearizing a
country.
Or just Singh Kashapa says, "Has there
ever been a real proper gene study that
studies that proves the RN invasion
migration story and is R1 A1A not found
in South India?"
The Aran invasion migration theory has
nothing to do with genetics. My dear
friends, let me tell you why.
What is the central claim
of the Arian invasion migration theory?
It has two central claims. First,
Sanskrit is foreign to India. Second,
Hinduism is foreign to India. Okay,
Sanskrit and Hinduism are foreign to
India. These are the central claims of
the RN invasion theory. How can you
prove or disprove that with genetics?
If you take my DNA, can it tell you what
language I spo speak? What my mother
tongue is? Can it tell you what my
religion is? It can't.
If let's say I I become mad tomorrow and
I convert to a foreign Abrahamic
religion for example will my DNA change
because I converted
or let's say from tomorrow I decide to
speak a Russian only will my DNA change
because of that DNA has nothing to do
with the central claims of the Arian
invasion migration myth
so no matter how much DNA research you
do it's not going to change anything
right and is R1 A1A not found in South
India they find there is plenty of R1
A1A in South India even in the far east
of India all across India it's all over
the place okay right
Pashankumar says top economist says M
would weaken in is it if it rises what's
University of Mexico
what's M I'm not sure I'm sorry I'm sure
you're trying to put some flags there
but I am not able to see them here sorry
millin says many Boeing jets failed
still. Why do airlines buy it? I think
they used to buy Boeing jets back in the
day and all those orders are still
coming in and the performance issues and
the recent issues of Boeing are are a
rather new thing just in the past few
years because the standards have
declined.
Uh Rahul Ladu says your thoughts on
madam president issuing inquiry on XCG.
I have no idea and I don't talk about
internal politics internal politics. So
not my cup of tea. Tjis says, "I hope
you're well, Tjis. I I heard about you
had some health issues. I hope you're
doing well, sir. Do well. Can AI lead to
extinction of humanity?"
Well, if you if you give AI agency and
if that AI is is super intelligent or
even AGI, then it can lead to the
extinction of humanity. If AI decides
that we are a nuisance and a burden to
the planet and we give it agency, which
means the tools to make real world
changes in the world, then yeah, it can
lead to the extinction of humanity. So
if you give AI access to real world
systems like weapons systems, like
decision-m systems, like big red buttons
and all that, yeah, it can certainly
lead to the extinction of humanity.
Dir says, "What should India do to stop
Trump's parks, Trump's Pakistan
assistance? Can we still break it apart
despite his business interests there?"
What should India do to stop Trump's
Pakistan assistance? Nothing. We cannot
do anything. He is hellbent on on
investing in Pakistan. He has about $65
trillion to extract from there which
includes cryptocurrency investments
which includes rare earth minerals and
oil and gas and whatnot. So he is
investing his own money into Pakistan
and once he has decided to do that what
can we do about it? So one thing that
can dissuade Trump from investing in
Pakistan if if is is if Pakistan becomes
super unstable.
I'm not suggesting anything here. I'm
just saying.
Okay. Uh Dra, sorry. Danch says, "Always
wanted to know your thoughts about Jim
Corbett. He was a poacher. He killed
tigers. Reading him out. He looks like a
naturalist, but history is often
distorted. Also, do you like going to
safaris?" I have never had time to go to
safaris. Sorry. I would love to. I would
love to see lions and tigers, but I'm
always busy doing some work. Jim Corbett
was a poacher. He used to kill tigers.
Evil guy.
United Alliances India can use IVF
method to stab stabilize TFR ratio or we
can do it the good old fashioned way.
Okay.
Uh Nikl says recent large increase in
German budget. Do you think the reason
behind this is to secure Germany's
position in Europe after America shifts
its focus? America is likely to shift
its focus to the Indo Pacific. Yes. And
therefore if that happens and America
says gets gets tired of Europe then the
Americans want to leave Europe in a big
shambles they don't want Europe to ever
rise again because when they think of
the rise of Europe they they mentally
see those marching jacks and the Hugo
boss uniforms of the of the third Reich
right so they don't want this to happen
so they want Europe to be in a complete
state of disrepair and shambles when
they leave which is why they are pushing
in millions and trillions and gazillions
of im of certain kinds of immigrants
into into into Europe. That's what the
Americans their their end game is, their
their exit strategy is. Uh but yes,
Germany wants to increase its budget. So
maybe they're thinking that thinking
could be that if America kind of takes
its focus away from Europe, then maybe
we could have the next big Reich and we
could be the next big power in Europe
once again. Maybe maybe it's a
possibility.
Uh Kuro says can or should India create
a branch military branch like USMC
Marine Corps for rapid response inv or
invasion? To my knowledge India only has
three naval infantry battalions that may
be outdated. Chinese by the way has
seven brigades. I could not agree with
you more sir.
India should have a marine corps. India
should have expeditionary capabilities.
India should have amphibious landing
vessels. India should have these things.
India lacks these things. We have the
Marcos which are marine commandos but
they're not a Marine Corps. We should
have a Marine Corps. You are completely
right. And yeah, I'm I'm glad you
brought this up over here today. India
should have expeditionary capabilities.
Mistal class ships or whatever. We can
buy them from the French if if required
and so on. Amphi amphibious landing
ships which in which big ships in which
you can you know have amphibious tanks
and whatnot. All kinds of things you can
bring in for a landing operation. Let's
say tomorrow morning we decide that we
will land in Karachi with uh 10,000
troops and 500 tanks. I'm just giving up
throwing out draft numbers. So after
suppressing the local air defenses and
other defenses. Yeah. So yeah, we should
have these capabilities, amphibious
capabilities, marine expeditionary
capabilities. You raise a very good
point. I agree. We should have it.
MK says, "Despite having the largest
empire in global resources, why was
Britain shaken and on the defensive
against Germany in World War II?"
Germany was hit hard in World War I.
Germany was hit hard in World World War
I. German Germany was humiliated in the
treaty of Vai but Germany Germany was
not destroyed.
So there was an inter war period between
1918 approximately to 1939
the 20 21 years in which Germany
rebuilt.
The rebuilding started with the coming
to power of the painter and he
transformed the German economy and all
that. And uh what happened is that
Germany had a tremendous education
system focused on science and
technology. And that's why they were
able to leverage that, weaponize that
and and create this gigantic high-tech
military machine, the best technology of
its time. And they just turned out
turnurned out airplanes and metas
smmiths and fauky wolfes and and and
henkels and shookas and the tiger tanks
and whatnot and ubots unasi boots in so
many large numbers. So that's why
Britain was shaken and on the defensive.
They had never expected Germany to put
up this all of this. You know that's
what happened.
Um, Purusham says, "What's what was the
point of attacking Russia's bombers?"
Well, to decimate their air fleet, their
their strategic bombing capabilities.
It's it's a worthy aim for an if you're
an adversary of Russia.
I mean, if you if you can take out 30%
of the strategic bomb fleet, I mean,
this is a huge huge achievement.
It makes Russia look weak in front of
the world. It undermines the morale of
the country. It shakes the confidence of
the leadership in the military. Come on.
What's the point? Are you kidding me?
Anul says, "How to develop iron will? By
putting yourself regularly in difficult
positions and doing things that are
uncomfortable for you and still doing
it. You do it over and over again, then
you'll develop an iron will."
Nanda Kishar says, "How much does it
cost for a private dinner for you? I am
not available on rent, sir. It costs way
too much. It costs I'm not available
like that for a private dinner.
Uh sorry Vun says Jind from Adogra from
Jammu Jen sir do you think making Jammu
province a separate state and making
Kashmir province a permanent union
territory can be good. I think it is the
right way forward. It is the only
correct way forward. Make Jammu province
a separate state and make the valley of
Kashmir this little thing a permanent
union territory. That is the right way
forward. Ladak can be a separate union
territory. It already is. But why merge
Jammu with the Kashmir Kashmir valley
with Kashmir province? Make Kashmir a
separate permanent union territory and
make Jammu a separate state. That is the
right way forward. I completely agree
with you sir.
Okay. Aditkumar says what's your
thoughts on 500,000 Chinese students
coming to the US this year is announced
by Trump. Did he bend the knee to Xi?
We'll see. It's an ongoing situation.
Trump is the master of the art of the
deal. He's the big biggest, baddest,
greatest negotiator in the world. It's
all transaction, transaction,
transaction for him. So, we don't know
what it means thus far. We'll look into
it and we'll see what it really means.
Will he actually allow half a million
Chinese students into the US?
I I doubt it. We'll see about that.
Trump won't bend the knee to she. He's
got too big of an ego for that to
happen. So, we'll see. Okay, ladies,
gentlemen, friends, all of you. This is
the end of today's live stream. It went
way past what we expected one and a half
hours plus. Uh so I will end it over
here. Uh thank you everybody for all the
questions. I really enjoyed this. It was
good fun. I think I'm glad I switched
the the the
super chats back on again. I think it
was better. Okay. So I will have another
live stream tomorrow. Tomorrow Saturday
I think it is. It is. We're going to
have a proper live stream tomorrow. Long
one. Uh and I'll take your questions
again over there. So, I look forward to
having you on that live stream. I look
forward to taking your questions,
answering them. And as always, keep
asking questions, keep learning, keep
thinking, keep questioning, and keep
raising your qu your your standards.
I'll see you very soon. Thank you.
Bye-bye.